hey everyone welcome back to our Tosca
automation playlist and we are talking
about Tosca best practices now prior to
this I have already shown you two best
practices and this is the third in the
series
now if you want to watch our previous
videos or if you want to watch our next
videos I would like you to subscribe to
our Channel first
so talking about the best practice
number three and it is about module
attribute usage
now we have seen what is a module and
what are the different module attributes
related to that particular module in
Tosca
and you create a module by scanning your
application
right so as per this best practice
you should limit your module attributes
and categorize them based on the module
functionality
now what do you mean by this is you
should not add all the module attributes
into a single module you should divide
your model attributes as per the module
functionality so create different
folders create different modules are
based on the functionality of the
application you are trying to scan
so let's try to understand this with the
help of an example
so I'll go back to my Tosca and here I
have put together
two examples okay both are for the same
screen okay so we are trying to scan
this enter vehicle data
and there are several Fields as you can
see right and some of them are mandatory
Fields some of them are optional Fields
And there are some headers some Footers
on this particular page okay and I have
scanned uh this particular page to
create my module now I have done it in
two ways okay
so in the first way I have categorized
my module attributes which are the
fields in the application in different
modules so you can see there is a
headers module and there is a enter
vehicle data module which contains the
fields in that particular page and then
there is also a headers module which
contains the auto by link which is what
I'm trying to scan okay and these are
all the fields for the automobile screen
now on the right hand side I have
created the same module but in a
different way now what I have done is I
have scanned that page and I have added
all my controls
together in this single module
now you may think that if you go ahead
and scan all the elements on your page
so you may not required to go back and
scan that application or that page again
so you can reuse this module for all
test cases but that is not an efficient
way of doing it and there are specific
reasons for this so if you go ahead and
create modules like this where you scan
all the controls of your application and
put together in just a single module
firstly your performance will be
impacted
also in the long run your workspace size
will also increase
okay because even if you're not using
the controls you are still scanning all
the controls and keeping it in the
modules okay rather than this what
presenters suggests is create the
modules but only use the model
attributes which you are going to use it
in your test case
now if you want to use more controls
than this okay so some other test case
requires some other controls which you
have not scanned um first time so you
can always go back and rescan that
particular window and add your
additional controls
but you should not go ahead and put all
the controls or scan all the controls in
just one module okay also you should
categorize your modules the reason is
pretty simple once you categorize you
create a structure in your modules and
when you drag this into your test cases
the same structure is maintained so
there is a test case flow with all the
different steps which are nothing but
your modules right now if I have got
just one module and I'm trying to use
that module in every test step then
maybe uh you have to rename all the test
steps and also while executing Tosca has
to go through all the module all the
module attributes in order to find that
particular module attribute which may
not be efficient right so think like
this if I just need to click on the
automobile link I just need to pass this
module which has got just one module
attribute but if I have to do the same
thing in this example then there are so
many module attributes out of this Tosca
has to click on the automobile link
right so it affects the performance of
your Automation and also it slows down
your execution also
um it impacts your workspace size so
there are lots of disadvantages as you
can see and also you can also make out
which looks better right the structured
way is much better than the
non-structured way right
so transcendus always recommends this
that use your modules uh in different
categories okay categorize your model
attributes and also uh make it more
efficient don't add all the module
attributes together right
so that's all for this particular video
I hope you enjoyed it and you learned
something new today if you want to
continue learning about best practices
keep watching for uh the upcoming videos
so until the next video
keep learning and keep watching our
videos